Never Forget. Never Forgive.
Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street is a
drama, horror film directed by Tim Burton.
The infamous story of Benjamin Barker, a.k.a Sweeney Todd, who sets up a barber shop down in
London which is the basis for a sinister partnership with his fellow tenant, Mrs.
Based on the hit Broadway musical.
Sweeney Todd, played by Johnny Depp.
Mrs. Lovett, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Judge Turpin, played by Alan Rickman.
Beadle, played by Timothy Spall.
Pirelli, played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Anthony, played by Jamie Campbell Bower.
Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street is a 2007 Gothic musical slasher film directed by Tim Burton from a screenplay by John Logan, based on the
stage musical of the same name by Stephen Sondheim and Hugh Wheeler, which in turn is based on the 1970 play Sweeney Todd by Christopher Bond.
The film retells the melodramatic Victorian tale of Sweeney Todd
(Johnny Depp), an English barber and serial killer.
After arriving in London, Todd seeks revenge on Judge Turpin (Alan Rickman) who
wrongfully convicted and exiled him in order to steal his wife.
Sweeney Todd murders his customers and, with the help of his accomplice, Mrs.
Lovett (Helena Bonham Carter), processes their corpses into meat pies.
The film marks the first collaboration between Depp, Bonham Carter, Rickman, Spall and
Baron Cohen (the second being Alice Through the Looking Glass in 2016).
Having been struck by the cinematic qualities of the stage musical while a college student,
Burton had entertained the notion of a film version since the early 1980s.
However, it was not until 2006 that he had the opportunity to realize this ambition, when
DreamWorks Pictures announced his appointment as replacement for director Sam Mendes.
Sondheim, although not directly involved, was
extensively consulted during production.
Depp, not known for his singing, took lessons in
preparation for his role, which producer Richard D.
Zanuck acknowledged was something of a gamble.
Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street had its premiere at the Ziegfeld Theater in New York City on 3 December
2007, and was released in the United States on 21 December 2007 and in the United Kingdom on 25 January 2008.
The film received critical acclaim, and was praised for the performances of the cast,
musical numbers, costume and set design, and faithfulness to the musical.
It grossed over $153 million against a production budget of $50 million.
Since its release, the film has been widely assessed as one of
the greatest musical films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of widow, asylum, confession, razor, villain.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.